UPAMA CHAKMA

Phone: +8801866609470

E-mail: upama.chakma@northsouth.edu;

Address: H# 79 R# 12 Block F, Bashundhara R/A, Dhaka1229

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/upama-chakma



SUMMARY: An experienced professional who is passionate to drive business excellence by utilizing skillsets in data analysis, finance, trade marketing & retail operations. Have worked in FMCG (BATB), done marketing consultancy and am also a proud & contributing alumni of the several NSU clubs & societies.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

British American Tobacco, Dhaka (FEB 2019 - JUN 2019)

Xcelerate Graduate Intern, Rotation across Marketing & Treasury Finance

- Ensured in-time financial closure support for a range of product categories.
- Conducted Data Analysis (using IBM Lotus & BATB Business Intelligence tools)
- Managed complex consultations and negotiations with stakeholders.
- Supported Import/Export processing, Letter of Credit Issuance, Fund Management, PO Issuance
- Followed-up on payable collections & extending credit, as per business policy.
- Conceptualized compliant visual merchandising, in relations to statutory & business guidelines.

Bridge Blue Global, Dhaka (OCT 2018 - DEC 2018)

Marketing & Social Media Manager

Managing all the communications for project deployments (external & internal)

- Digital content (Social Media & Web) management
- Physical material design & production overview
- Events Planning & Execution

VOLUNTARY CONTRIBUTIONS:

1. MEMBER OF INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS CLUB

It is the sole business club of NSU that provides a platform for its students to engage in extracurricular activities.

Awarded as the top performer in Spring of 2016

2. CASE COMPETITIONS & PROJECT

- 2nd Runner Up in Petromax LPG Limited Inter University business competition BIZ ACES 2018
- Participated in Socio camp 7(Semi finalist), HR calibration 2018 (Semi finalist), Sellsation 2017

EDUCATION:

1. 2015-2019, NORTH SOUTH UNIVERSITY

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Bachelor of Business Administration (Marketing Major)

CGPA 3.12/4.00

Global Village Champion - International Business 372 – Intra NSU Global Village Exhibition – 2016

2. 2010 JAN - MILESTONE SCHOOL & COLLEGE, DHAKA

SSC Board Examination, Concentration: Business Studies GPA: 4.94/5.00

Merit Scholarship Recipient; Class Monitor in '10 & '11

3. 2013 JAN - HOLY CROSS COLLEGE, DHAKA

HSC Board Examination, Concentration: Business Studies GPA: 4.88/5.00

Class Monitor; Inter College Baseball Champion – 2011

REFERENCES:

Abdallah Talukdar Treasury Specialist, British American Tobacco Bangladesh Phone: +8801713653490 E-Mail: abdallah.talukdar@bat.com Mr. Ehfaz Nowman Lecturer, North South University

Phone: +880255668200

E-mail: ehfaznowman@northsouth.edu